# 隋坡
Sui Po
# 赶紧尝尝吧
Taste it
# 这是一个老菜
This is a traditional dish
# 几十年了
It has been decades
# 我十几岁的时候
When I was a teenager
# 在我师父他们家
In my master's home
# 他做过这个 连锅汤
He also cooked this 'Lian Guo Tang' (Soup-in-pot)
# 我说这还挺好的冬天
I would say it's really suitable for winter
# 这是猪的坐板儿肉
This is the 'zuo ban rou' pork (the cut on the butt)
# 就是煮回锅肉这块肉
which is also for 'Hui Guo Rou'
# 凉水下锅 得嘞
Boil from cold water. OK
# 凉水下锅把里边这个
Boil from cold water to
# 血沫子这些东西杂质慢慢的
let the scum and other stuff
# 就让它渗透出来
go out slowly
# 搁点葱姜
Add some green onion and ginger
# 搁点黄酒
Some Huangjiu rice wine
# 煮上了 煮多长时间
Boil it now. For how long?
# 只要能扎透就行了
As long as you can pierce it
# 还不能煮太烂了
Don't cook it too hard
# 把萝卜切成骨牌片
Cut the radish into dominoes-shaped slices
# 焙点花椒面
Prepare some baked Sichuan peppercorn powder
# 小火
Low heat
# 把花椒炒香
Cook the Sichuan peppercorn until you smell the aroma
# 隋坡给二伯看着那锅要开
Sui Po, keep an eye on the pot. It's boiling
# 打沫子 好嘞
Remove the scum. Ok
# 沫子一定要打干净
Make sure you remove it completely
# 搁这边吧 倒那纸上
Place it here on the kitchen towel
# 晾上
Cool it a bit
# 下一步
Next step
# 豆瓣酱给剁一剁
Mince the doubanjiang
# 做这个兑碗汁的红油
To make the red chili oil
# 油
Oil
# 用热油来呲这个辣椒是吗
Fry the chili with hot oil, right?
# 辣椒给它洗一洗
Wash the chili peppers
# 往辣椒粉上倒了点凉油
Add some cold oil onto the chili pepper powder
# 辣椒酱
Chili sauce
# 倒点凉油给它拌一拌
Add some cold oil and stir it
# 难免糊了
to avoid burning
# 大爷这差不多了 （油温）五成热
Da Ye, this is almost ok. The oil temperature is at 150 degrees Celsius
# 这个热油不能一下下去
You should not add all the hot oil in one go
# 要不然就糊了 一点一点的
Otherwise it's gonna be burnt. Slowly, little by little
# 这个辣椒酱得挖个小洞
Dig a small hole in the center of the sauce
# 让这油从里往外（加）热
Let the oil heat it from the center to the surrounding
# 这得高点 这油温
The oil temperature needs to be higher
# 它不会溅出 溅的哪都是
It will not splash everywhere
# 然后再呲这边这个
Then fry this one here
# 水洗以后
After washing
# 就炸的特别爆香
It smells very nice
# 三椒合一
Mixture of the three kinds of chili peppers
# 酥香 干香 酱香
Crispy-aroma, dry-aroma, and sauce-aroma
# 这个就行了
This is done
# 下边呢 下边把酱油做了
Now let's prepare the soysauce
# 网友们看着啊
Look, friends
# 二伯要把酱油熬一下
Er Bai is going to boil the soysauce
# 其实很多酱油
In fact, for most types of soysauce
# 都应该把它呲熟了
you should boil them before use
# 熟了更香
Smells better after boiled
# 我把萝卜弄一下 齐了
Let me deal with the radish, and it'll be done
# 这个萝卜这个臭气味
The bad smell of the radish...
# 就一样东西能解就是冰糖
Can only be eliminated by one thing. White rock sugar.
# 别的都解不了
Nothing else works
# 这刚才您没说 还藏一个小诀窍
You didn't say that in the beginning. That's a hidden trick
# 水开了
Water is boiling
# 下萝卜焯水
Blanch the radish
# 二伯小绝招啊
Small trick from Er Bai
# 焯萝卜的时候搁点冰糖
Add some white rock sugar while blanching the radish
# 去掉萝卜的苦味 涩味和臭气味
to remove its bitterness and bad smell
# 好了
Done
# 捞出
Take it out
# 焯完了冲一下凉
Rinse with cold water after blanching
# 也是在去掉萝卜的臭气味
This is also removing the bad smell
# 先擀这个花椒面
Crush the Sichuan peppercorn
# 我们把花椒炒好以后
After heating the Sichuan peppercorn
# 放在纸上面擀的时候
Crush it on the kitchen towel
# 它会更干松
It's going to be drier and more crispy
# 花椒味还很少能进到
Its smell and flavor will not penetrate
# 木的案板当中去
into the chopping board
# 比较好清洁
It's good for cleaning
# 嘿 精细
Hey. That's a fine job
# 下一步咱们就调个汁儿
Now let's prepare a sauce
# 郫县豆瓣酱 炸熟了的
Doubanjiang. Fried
# 然后来一把花椒面
With a handful of Sichuan peppercorn powder
# 你这不是一把
This is not a handful
# 您这一捏捏
This is a 'fingerful'
# 红油
Red oil
# 干辣椒油
Chili oil
# 酱油
And soy sauce
# 我再把葱花搁上去
Let me add the minced green onion
# 星星点点
Minced bits
# 好 齐活
Ok. Done
# 肉煮好了
The pork is ready
# 二伯 你歇会啊 我给你切切肉
Er Bai, take a break. Let me cut the meat for you
# 越薄越好
The thinner the better
# 够薄吗 够薄
Thin enough? Yes
# 我得按着二伯的要求
I need to follow Er Bai's orders
# 二伯考验我呢
He is testing me
# 你看这肉煮的特别好
See? The meat is well cooked
# 带点溏心
Slightly raw in the middle
# 待会咱一煮
When we boil it later
# 香气就出来了 是不是大爷
The aroma is going to come out. Isn't it, Da Ye?
# 二伯 您查查行不行
Er Bai, please check this
# 您太地道了大爷
That's really authentic, Da Ye!
# 我是切不出来
I cannot do this
# 来 咱们继续
Come on, let's continue
# 这是煮肉的原汤
This is the original broth when boiling the pork
# 这个不能给扔了 这原汤非常好
You shouldn't throw it away. The broth is great
# 开火 开火啦
Turn on the heat. Heat is on
# 先放肉 其实这个肉为什么先放啊
Add the meat first. Why add the meat first?
# 因为我们切的时候它还有点溏心
Because it's still a bit raw in the middle
# 这个煮出来的肉呈小碗状
The boiled pork slices will turn into the shape of a bowl
# 放了点花椒 提出花椒的香味
Add some Sichuan peppercorns. That's activating the aroma of the peppercorns
# 盐
Salt
# 然后白胡椒粉 行了
Then white pepper powder. Done
# 这肉起变化了
The meat is changing in shape
# 有点小碗状了啊 打卷了
Now they look like small bowls. Becoming curved
# 大爷切这肉炒回锅肉绝了
The pork slices cut by Da Ye is awesome for cooking Hui Guo Rou
# 好 锅开了二伯
Ok. It's boiling, Er Bai
# 萝卜什么时候放
When do we add the radish?
# 赶紧下吧大爷
Right now, Da Ye
# 这里边花椒都篦出来
Filter the peppercorns out
# 肉呢蘸上这汁儿吃
Dip the pork into the sauce
# 然后这汤呢 我们可以喝汤
And the soup... We can have the soup
# 愿意吃酸辣口 你看
If you prefer the sour-spicy flavor... You see
# 醋 香菜 白胡椒粉
Vinegar, coriander, and white pepper powder
# 自己一调 能吃两个味道
You can create two flavors by yourself
# 给大家看 上边一点油都没有
Show this to everyone. No oil drops on the surface
# 汤清 萝卜烂糊
The soup is clear. The radish is very soft
# 这冬天来点这个
Have this dish in winter
# 这一家人多温暖啊
You will enjoy your time warmly with your family
# 起锅装盘
Ready to serve
# 齐活
Done!
# 先喝汤了啊二伯
Er Bai, we can have the soup first
# 汤鲜 没有萝卜的臭味
The soup is very delicious. No bad smell from the radish
# 吃这个得这么吃
You can have this dish in this way
# 一种方式先喝汤 后吃肉
One way is to enjoy the soup first, and the meat later
# 你看二伯调这汁
Look at Er Bai's sauce
# 大爷挺辣的 您挑底下
Da Ye, this is spicy. Pick from the bottom
# 没事 就不怕辣
It's fine. I am not afraid of spicy food
# 它是两种口感
Now it's giving a different feeling
# 刚才是汤鲜味美 现在呢
It was delicious and umami previously. Now,
# 香辣
it's aromatic and spicy
# 这豆瓣酱搁的好
The doubanjiang is well prepared
# 酱香 醇厚
Smells nice and thick in flavor
# 隋坡 赶紧尝尝吧
Sui Po, taste it
# 你先喝汤先体验一下
Have the soup first
# 因为你要先吃辣的
Since if you taste the spicy first
# 再一喝汤瞎了
It'll ruin the soup
# 就体现不出这汤的味了 可是呢
You won't enjoy the original flavor of the soup. However,
# 冰糖加里边焯这个白萝卜 确实好
Blanching the radish with rock white sugar
# 这绝对是一窍门 确实好
This is definitely a trick. Amazing
# 今儿可来着了
It's worth it today
# 确实 大约有
Indeed. It's been already...
# 三十年四十年都不做了
30 to 40 years since I cooked this dish last time
# 但是最让我赞美的
The part that I praise the most
# 焯萝卜搁了两块冰糖
is to add some rock sugar while blanching the radish
# 去掉萝卜的臭味 苦味 涩味
which removes the bad smell, bitterness, and unpleasant flavor
# 这个小诀窍非常经典
This is a classic trick
# 给二伯点个赞
Thumb up for Er Bai!
# 谢谢大爷 谢谢隋坡
Thank you, Da Ye! Thank you, Sui Po!